EMILE GIVENTAL

!!! 10/22/98

@ emilegivental@gmail.com

510-221-9540

% www.emilegivental.com

in LinkedIn

O github.com/egivental

EDUCATION

M.S.E. in Computer Science

University of Pennsylvania School of Engineering and Applied Science

2020 - 2021

Philadelphia, PA

- 3.7 GPA in departmental CS courses.
- Coursework in AI/ML, WebDev, Web Systems (AWS), and Problem Solving workshops.
- Sub-matriculated into program as Sophomore. Took courses in Randomized Algorithms/Cryptography and Computer Graphics while still attending Haverford.

B.S. Double Major in Mathematics and Computer Science

Haverford and Bryn Mawr Colleges

2017 - 2020

Ardmore, PA

- 3.9 In Majors GPA
- Thesis on Interpretable Meta Learning
- Graduated in 3 years. Completed Computer Science Major at Haverford, while completing the Mathematics Major at Bryn Mawr.
- Varsity Athlete on Cricket Team

RESEARCH AND WORK EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Researcher

Haverford College Friedler Lab

June 2018 - January 2020

- Ardmore, PA
- Machine Learning Research on Interpretability and Fairness in Transfer/Meta Learning Environments
- Created a Pip Package wrapping 3 interpretable ML Models: Supersparse Linear Integer Model, Bayesian OR/AND Rule Lists, and Certifiably Optimal Rule Lists.

Teaching Assistant and Tutor

Haverford College

August 2018 - January 2020

Ardmore, PA

- Tutor sessions for debugging, using Github, and coding style
- Assisted with homework and provided supplementary instruction
- Creation of auto-grading software and manual grading
- Courses in Python and Java

PUBLICATION

Fair Meta-Learning: Learning How to Learn Fairly

Dylan Slack, Sorelle Friedler, Emile Givental

2019

- Accepted to NeurIPS 2019 for Workshop
- Accepted to ACM FAT* 2020 for Oral Presentation
- Studies Meta Learning (a preemptive form of transfer learning developed by Chelsea Finn) and its affects on the interpretability and fairness of algorithms in related domains.
- Research showed that regularizer terms for fairness and interpretability in Meta Learning models could work as well as in normal gradient descent models.

SUMMARY

I completed my undergraduate education in 3 years, and during those summers I chose to do research rather than internships. The summer after completing Haverford, I couldn't get any internships due to Covid. I am now seeking a full-time or internship position as a Software Engineer. I am interested in full stack software development, machine learning projects, and both back-end and front-end web development.

LANGUAGES/TOOLS

Python/C/C++/Java/JS | F

HTML/CSS

Tensorflow/Pytorch/Keras

Numpy/Pandas

React/Next.js

SQL/MongoDb

Express/Django/Spark
Linux/SSH/SCP

Eclipse/Maven

AWS (S3, RDS, EMR, EC2) Node/Yarn

Latex

Selenium/jest/JUnit Testing

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Python
- Package for using 3 Interpretable machine learning libraries. %
- Mulitple Class Projects with Pandas, Numpy, and various Machine Learning Libraries. *
- Pytorch based Machine Learning Research. *
- JS/React
- A Twitch/Twitter Clone. Tweets, Follows, and Livestreams. Back-end API, Front-End, and Database management.
- Java
- Web Server Framework. Conceivably, one could use this code to build their own static web server like they could use Django or Spark.
- A Google Clone built in a Graduate Web Systems Course.
- C/C++
- An OS with file management and commonly used linux terminal commands functionality.
 Taken at UPenn as Sophomore.
- Computer Graphics assignments from a graduate course, including a Minecraft Clone. Built with OpenGL. *
- A multithreaded Real Time Traffic System. *
- * Code unavailable for public repositories.

INTERESTS/HOBBIES

Stocks/Finance/Crypto Politics eSports
Poker Coffee Baseball Soccer

Read Company Stocks Mark Westweed